# **lestyn Gage**

**Software Engineer** 

https://www.iestyngage.com

### **Core Skills**

Full-Stack Development
Web & Mobile Development
Troubleshooting & Debugging
Agile Methodology
Code Review
User Experience
Documentation
Team Collaboration

## **Programming Languages**

JavaScript | TypeScript | HTML CSS Java | Swift | PHP | Python SQL

#### **Tools**

Git | Gitlab | GitHub | NodeJS Yarn | NPM | WSL | VSCode IntelliJ | Gradle | Jira | Excel Postman

#### Languages

English | First language
Welsh | Basic proficiency

#### **Interests**

Kayaking | Cooking | Climbing Reading | Gym | Baking | Cycling



## **Career summary**

Growth-focused Full Stack Software Engineer with a one-year achievement record in agile environments and experience combining all facets of software, web, and mobile development. Verifiable proficiency in developing innovative products and applications. Committed to excellence, readable, testable, and maintainable code.

## **Professional Experience**

CoreFiling | Oxford, England | Hybrid

Junior Software Engineer | 02/2021 - Present

Languages: Typescript, JavaScript, Java, HTML, CSS, Python

Frameworks: React, Django, Spring Boot, Liferay,

- Full-stack developer, with a focused on the front end.
- Pioneering new front-end pages and components to maximise usability, simplify navigation, and create a seamless user journey for a new product.
- Leveraging swagger to develop new APIs endpoints while also implementation back-end changes.
  - Performed code review for major and minor changes for multiple code bases
- Supporting QA and PM to identify and address pain points, bugs, and issues.
- Facilitating knowledge sharing and improved README.md and getting started documentation to streamline developer onboarding process
- Methodically documenting and managing defects, partnering with other team members in developing and implementing resolutions, and accelerating product improvement.

TalkOut Technology | Birmingham, England | Remote

Junior iOS Developer | 11/2020 - 12/2020

Languages: Swift,

Frameworks: SwiftUI, UIKit

- Supported a multi-discipline team in developing and releasing an iOS application.
- Produced UI tests and refactored generated code to enhance readability.
- Prototyped, and presented interactive widgets, increasing usability and enhancing the user experience.
- Reason for leaving: Team made redundant

Aberystwyth University | Aberystwyth, Wales

**Computer Science Demonstrator** | 10/2018 – 12/2018

• Mentored, guided, and supported first-year students in various programming topics, fixed code, and marked assignments, empowering students to enhance their programming skills.

## **Education & Qualifications**

2017-2020

Aberystwyth University First Class Honours

BSc Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence University Projects:

• Created a Conference iOS application for a Mobile Development module's

- assignment
  Java based project where I generated and solved "Rush Hour" puzzle using AI in addition there was a UI element where you could create your own levels as well as
- **Personal Projects**

play randomly generated levels

- Created my own personal website using 11ty
- Used a Evolutionary Algorithm to complete the Card problem

Referees available upon request